gudrunsjoden.com 2019-09-06

# Privacy and Security Statement | Gudrun Sjödén

HOW WE HANDLE YOUR PERSONAL DATA

When you shop with us, you provide your personal data and accordingly you permit us to store and use it in order to fulfill our obligations to you, and in order to provide you with the best possible service and offerings.

We do not give out your data for marketing purposes to any parties outside of Gudrun Sjödén. We only give your data to our trusted partners and suppliers (in some cases outside of the EU) when this is necessary to fulfill our commitments.

We use your personal data in the following ways:

**When shopping in our webshop**  
In order for us to be able to manage your purchase, we save your name, address, email address, phone number, payment information, payment history and order information. We use your data to process your order and any returns, to send your delivery status, handle payments, and to provide you with the best possible service when you contact us.

We store your data as long as you are an active customer and as long as you have the right to submit a complaint, which is 36 months after your last purchase, unless authorities require the data to be saved for a longer period. We use it when we carry out our part of our joint purchase agreement.

**Customer service**  
In order for us to provide you with the best service when you need answers to questions, technical support or advice via email, our chat function, phone or our social media platforms, we must handle your data. The data we process includes your name, address, phone number, potentially your birthday, payment information, payment history, potentially credit information, order information, customer number and any previous correspondence.

We keep your data from phone calls for 90 days, from conversations via email for 24 months, and other data about you is saved for 36 months after your last purchase. Processing this information is necessary in order to, in our common interest, be able to offer you the help and support of customer service.

**Marketing**  
We use your personal data to inform you about our products and services via mail, email, text message, telephone, social media or other similar electronic channels. To be able to do this, we process your name, email address, phone number and your address. To get to know you and be able to offer you information about products we think you will like, we also process data about what items you have bought or shown interest in.

Processing your personal data is based on your consent when you agree to receive marketing. The exception is for direct marketing via mail (including catalogs), marketing via social media and carefully selected offers via email, which are sent to you based on your interest when you make a purchase from us. This data is stored for up to 36 months but at any time, you may contact us to end such processing.

**My pages**  
To give you easy access to and the ability to manage your information (such as contact information, order history, details of your orders, subscriptions etc.), we process your personal data.

To be able to carry this out, we use the data that you have shared with us, such as your name, phone number, address, email address, order history and customer number. This data is stored and processed as long as you are an active customer with us, i.e. up to 36 months after your last purchase, or until you choose to delete your account. This processing is based on our common interest as this data is required in order to offer the service.

**The Gudrun Club**  
We use your data in order to manage your benefits in the club and to send news and offers about our products and services to you via mail, email, text message, social media or other similar electronic channels. To be able to do this, we will process data such as your name, address, email address and customer number. To provide you with personal offers, we also use your order history.

We store your data as long as you are a member of our club or as long as you are an active customer with us, i.e. 36 months after your last purchase. This processing is necessary for the agreement to membership in the loyalty program.

**Contests**  
When you enter contests, we process your data in order to contact you with information about the contest, to contact the winners and to send and follow up on prizes. To be able to do this, we process your contact information (name, address and phone number), any email address and information that is submitted for the contest.

We save this data until the contest is closed, the winners have been contacted and the prizes have been distributed. Processing your personal data is based on your permission when you choose to enter our contest.

**Cookies**  
Our website uses cookies. A cookie is a small text file stored on your computer/mobile device containing no personal information. Cookies saved while visiting our website are called temporary cookies – they disappear when you close the web browser. Cookies saved for a longer period are called permanent cookies. At any time, you can disable cookies in your web browser settings, where you can indicate that cookies are not permitted. However, this will mean that you cannot make use of the full functionality of the website, because our webshop’s functionality is based on the use of cookies.

To give you the best possible experience, we use both temporary cookies and permanent cookies in our webshop. These cookies enable, for example, saving products in your shopping cart, being logged off the site after a certain period of inactivity, and receiving relevant information.

We use cookies to analyze and improve your experience on our website, for example through third-party cookies from Google Analytics. Cookies used for analysis are both temporary cookies that save information about your session and permanent cookies that remember you when you return to our site at a later date.  
We use third-party cookies to make it possible for you to easily share our content on social media. We also use permanent third-party cookies in order to provide you with relevant offers from us when you visit other websites/social networks.

YOUR RIGHTS

According to the General Data Protection Regulation you are entitled to know what information we have registered about you. For a record excerpt or data portability, please refer to our customer service. If you would like to modify the data we have received from you (for example, if you feel it is incorrect, incomplete or irrelevant), it is easiest to do so by logging in to “My pages” on our website, or by contacting our customer service. Here, you can also modify or stop subscribing to our marketing mailings or to other things to which you have given consent. Do you want to be removed from our database? If so, please contact our customer service and we will help you.

You have the right to object to processing of the data we collect based on the balancing of interests, but at the risk that we cannot offer you certain functions. In the unlikely event that you feel we are handling your data erroneously you have the right to present your complaint to a regulatory authority. 

OTHER

**Encryption**  \- we safeguard your data in our webshop using encryption. SSL stands for Secure Sockets Layer and is a feature that encrypts all information sent between buyer and seller.

**Links**  \- Here on www.gudrunsjoden.com there may be links to other websites. Gudrun Sjödén Design AB takes no responsibility for the privacy protection or content of these sites.

**Copyright**  \- All content on our webshop is protected by copyright.

**Personal data controller** – Gudrun Sjöden Design AB, corporate registration number 556193-8233.
